Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The White Base made contact with
the Zanzibar captained by Char...
L...but it was unable to shoot it down.
The most that the Gundam was able to do
was defeat the mobile armor Bigro.
Breakthrough
Could it be reinforcements?
There's another mobile suit approaching.
Where are the guys who hit the showers?
On the decks, maintaining their machines.
Fraw Bow, launch one or two of them.
Who should we send out?
Whoever's in the best condition.
Hayato, then?
Tell him to hurry.
Hayato, please head out in the Guntank.
All machines remain on standby.
I'll prepare the Guntank for a sortie.
So it's just one enemy craft?
We're counting on you, Hayato!
Okay!
You're only sending out the Guntank?
Mr. Kai's still in the shower room...
I understand. I've got a few ideas myself.
Have Hayato go on ahead.
Amuro says he'll launch in the Gundam too.
Is that all right?
That's fine. Let him launch.
Sayla. Why don't you lie down for a while.
Use one of the rooms in the gravity block.
But the enemy...
We've got Lieutenant Sleggar to cover you.
Get some rest. That's an order.
Y-Yes, sir.
I'll do that.
What were the results of her medical exam?
Nothing out of the ordinary.
She's in perfect health.
Is that so.
I'm proceeding on a direct course.
Contact with the enemy in 110 seconds.
Then I'll cut the radio.
That must be it.
Wh-What's that mobile armor?
It's different from the last one.
So Dimitri took off?
Even though I clearly warned him not to?
Why did you let him do it,
without my authorization?
I'm sorry to say this, Captain Char...
...but you would have stopped him
from avenging Lieutenant Tokwan.
Besides, Dimitri already has experience
as a test pilot for the mobile armor Zakrello.
I've never heard of such a mobile armor.
It was abandoned
before it could be properly tested.
But Dimitri said that
the Zakrello's diffuse beam cannon...
I told you that this is our own backyard.
Right now, we can even contact
Dren's patrol fleet for assistance.
All right.
I know how you all respected Tokwan, but...
Dimitri must return as soon as he's satisfied.
Yes, sir! Thank you very much, sir!
If anything like this ever happens again
you will be court-martialed, Lieutenant.
That's fast. It's different from the last one...?
It's loaded with missiles, too...?!
One more shot oughtta wipe out
that mobile armor-wannabe!
Did I miss it...?!
I didn't hit it! Hayato, just hang in there...!
Another mobile suit?! But it's awfully fast.
What could possibly have such speed?
Here it comes!
This guy's annoying!
Fine, I'll take care of that clunker first!
Gotcha!
You fool. Same old move!
No mistake.
I made a direct hit to his engine.
My computer predicted his moves easily.
What was he trying to do anyway?
Amuro? Do you read me?
Destruction of mobile armor confirmed.
Please return at once.
No enemy movements currently detected.
Roger. Two hits taken by Gundam.
I'll return to the ship quickly.
What's wrong?
Did two battles in a row tire you out?
No. Gundam's right arm was damaged, sir.
But we've wiped out the immediate enemies.
There's no need to be so hasty.
You're only saying that because
you don't know Char, Lieutenant.
He'll be after us soon with a new plan.
Every other word on the bridge is "Char".
Is he really that special?
He thinks quickly on his feet.
He even pilots mobile suits himself.
He's incredible!
I'd love to meet this Char guy.
Don't you need to get more rest?
I'm... fine.
Amuro, take a break.
I'll look after things here.
Thank you. I'll head up to the bridge.
Ms. Sayla...
Lieutenant! What about the main cannons?
No big deal!
Mr. Bright will yell at you. We're in combat.
You're a pest, you know that?
Yeah.
Let's talk again when things quiet down.
Sure.
It's always about my brother, isn't it...
Can we contact the Camel fleet?
Yes, sir! We're tracing its
course on the computer.
Open up a laser comm channel.
Yes, sir!
Uh, Captain...
Hm?
I'm very sorry about what happened
with Dimitri earlier.
Forget it. I couldn't care less
about a weapon I wasn't even aware of.
Right...
You'll make it up to me one day, Mulligan.
Y-Yes, sir.
It's Lieutenant Dren of the Camel fleet.
It's been awhile, Lt. Commander Char...
Or rather, it's Captain Char now, isn't it.
You haven't changed a bit, Dren.
Sir.
We're pursuing the Trojan Horse.
From where your ships are right now
you should be able to interrupt them.
You share a fateful bond
with the Trojan Horse.
Roger. Can you catch up with us?
Dren... have you forgotten
whom you're talking to?
Forgive me, Captain.
Alter course, minus 110!
We're going after the Trojan Horse!
Artesia...
I can't ever forgive the Zabi family.
Please don't get in my way...
I can't approve of what you're doing, Casval.
So there are other sections of Gundam
that are still severed?
Please replace the TC-17 block too.
It took a hit.
Okay!
What's up?
Can we talk for a bit?
Sure, no problem.
I was wondering... What do I have to do
to quickly become a good pilot?
I think you're already
a good pilot, Ms. Sayla.
Don't flatter me, Amuro.
I want to survive, no matter what.
You're acting strange all of a sudden.
Even I'd like to stand a chance against Char.
No way! When he was using Zaku types
even I could fight him. But now he's...!
It was just an example, Amuro.
If only I were like you...
Fraw Bow!
Just a minute. I'm confirming the data.
Three enemy vessels detected
at one o'clock, 30 degrees overhead.
They appear to be Musai types.
Three Musai types detected!
Please go to battle stations!
The Zanzibar's behind us,
and the Musais before us.
We're going to have to break through them.
All hands, level 1 battle stations!
Entering first combat speed.
All machine guns, check defenses!
E.C.M. and laser searchers at maximum!
Disperse combat level Minovsky particles!
Here we go again.
Level 1 battle stations!
Let's go! Let's go!
Open machine gun turrets, main cannons,
mega particle cannons!
Listen well!
We'll use the same tactics as Captain Char.
We're sending six Rick Doms, Camel,
and Tokumel to attack the Trojan Horse!
I seem to have a fateful attraction to
the Trojan Horse and the Gundam.
All craft full speed!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Our targets have passed the F line.
They're Dom-type mobile suits.
The kind with skirts.
Fraw Bow! Send Lieutenant Sleggar
in the spare G-Fighter!
Yes, sir!
Lieutenant Sleggar! Please board
the G-Fighter on Deck 2!
What a pain. Wasn't I supposed to be
on the main cannons?
Hayato in the Guntank, heading out!
Whoa! You're pumped,
Corporal Hayato!
Then I'll join you.
Please take note.
Don't rely too much on this computer.
It's only accessible in G-Armor mode.
In other words, the G-Fighter
is manually operated?
Right.
Suits me fine.
Take care!
Sure thing!
Bright. Do you think
Lieutenant Sleggar will be okay?
The Guntank and Guncannon
aren't suited for high-speed combat.
The more weapons we deploy, the better.
Reaching enemy in 90 seconds.
The Musais are also closing
at maximum combat speed!
Sayla! Time to wake up...
Ms. Sayla's already on Deck 2.
She wants to launch.
I see. Is she alright?
Are you feeling okay?
I'm fine, Amuro.
They're not the mobile suits
from the Zanzibar, right?
I'm feeling a little out of sorts,
so I'll work it off with some action.
Sayla. You're acting strange.
Think so? I feel a lot better than I did earlier.
Don't worry about me.
Be careful.
How impertinent.
What's the Trojan Horse doing?
They seem to have detected the Musais.
They're increasing speed,
but staying on course.
Nice move. They're trying
to break through the Musais.
Order the Camel fleet to concentrate
all of their fire on the Trojan Horse!
Will do.
Accelerate Zanzibar 10 percent.
Stay on course after the Trojan Horse.
Meanwhile...
...having left Jaburo in South America...
...Admiral Tianem and his group of
the Federation's Second Combined Fleet...
...were leaving Earth's atmosphere.
They were setting a course for Luna II.
They're coming.
Now's my chance to prove
I'm a great pilot, too. Let's see now...
Let's do this.
Is that Mr. Sleggar?
You're jumping the gun!
At times like these, he who rushes... loses.
They've split into two groups.
In that case...
All right, if Hayato's going left, I'll go...
Why are both Kai and Lt. Sleggar
distancing themselves from the Guntank?!
If we separate just like the enemy,
there's no way we'll win.
Hm? Ms. Sayla?
Hayato, do you read me? We'll only win...
...if we coordinate with the others!
Those two think they can win on their own!
Roger that. Ms. Sayla and I will
move in behind Kai and Sleggar!
Roger!
Bastard!
Gotta lure him closer...!
Here?!
Go!
All right!
Man! You sure are a lot calmer
than I would've figured.
I misjudged you.
Wait a sec!
Oh no!
Bastards!
They're good!
Where's the last one?!
Fire at the area
where the Doms were destroyed!
Charge the Trojan Horse all at once!
Come in, White Base, do you read me?
Sayla here! We're heading back
to defend the White Base!
Please do! We need to get rid of the "skirts"
before we can start attacking the Musais.
So move it!
Block 6 has been hit!
It's the fourth hit!
The barrage is too weak!
The enemy's moving all around.
Tell them to just shoot without aiming.
Fraw Bow. Where's the Gundam?
Almost ready. Please wait.
The Musais have passed the F line
and fired beams!
I'll leave the evasive maneuvers to you.
Yes, sir!
Starboard!
Main cannons and mega particle cannons,
fire at the Musai's bridges or engines!
Fire!
Don't just shoot blindly! Aim carefully!
Direct hit to the portside Musai!
Who told you to aim for their turrets?!
If we destroyed the engine
they couldn't use their beam cannons.
Concentrate your fire!
Direct all shots to the portside Musai!
Don't even look at the others!
Sorry for the wait!
The Gundam's ready for takeoff!
Hurry! The Musais are our targets.
Ignore the skirted mobile suits!
Roger that!
Here I go!
A skirted suit!
T-Tokumel!
Order the two Rick Doms to retreat!
They're in our line of fire!
Camel, Swamel,
we'll destroy the Trojan Horse!
We must take them out
before Captain Char arrives!
Two Musais... coming now!
Gunners! Aim at the portside Musai!
Forget about the one to starboard!
What's that?! I can't hear!
There's no sign of the Gundam!
Whose Rick Dom is that?
It's Frasy's!
He says he hasn't seen the Gundam.
That's crazy!
Then where's it hiding?!
Did we get it?!
No! We hit one of their mobile suits!
We almost have them!
Don't let up fire!
That's impossible!
The Gundam must be there. Where is it?!
Lieutenant Dren!
What now?!
Something's approaching from bearing zero!
What is it?!
It seems to be a mobile suit!
High-temperature object approaching!
A missile?!
It's not directed at us!
Swamel?!
Swamel! Get out of the way!
I-It's the Gundam.
That white mobile suit...
It's the Gundam!
Above or below?!
Below!
Only the Musai is left!
Who would have thought that even Dren
couldn't hold his own until I arrived?
The Trojan Horse's course?
Are you sure about that?
Yes, sir.
If we take a direct route to Luna II...
...there's a 98 percent chance
we're going to run into the Zanzibar.
Very well. We'll head for Side 6.
I concur, Lieutenant.
Sorry I got the G-Fighter damaged...
Chief Petty Officer Amuro bawled me out.
You were in a hurry to score points, it seems.
Something like that.
But, Bright.
It's not really going to help us
if we head for Side 6...
If we fought the Zanzibar in our condition...
we'd have little chance of victory.
He's right.
It's obvious even from the outside
how badly the White Base is damaged.
Do you foresee any problems, Mirai?
No, not really... it's just...
Side 6 is a neutral Side.
The Antarctic Treaty prohibits
any kind of warfare there.
With luck, we can get the White Base repaired.
Of course, it's also possible we'd
be surrounded by Zeon.
Can't help that. We'll worry about it later.
What are the chances...?
Altering course.
Redirecting the White Base to Side 6.
Side 6.
Of all the Sides that existed...
...it was the only one unaffiliated with
the Principality of Zeon or the Federation...
...and not participating in the war.
All fighting is strictly prohibited
within Side 6 airspace.
Side 6, where reunions await.
Mirai with Cameron.
And Amuro with his father.
In war, are people inevitably
forced to shed tears?
And then there is Conscon, who laughs...
...and declares Char to be incompetent.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Farewell in Side Six.
Will you be able to survive?
Next Time
Farewell in Side Six
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...